Teodor Fratiloiu

teodor.fratiloiu@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/teodor-fratiloiu

Recent graduate of the Technical University of Munich with a M.Sc. in Electrical Engineering. Specialized in machine learning, cybersecurity and embedded systems, with a strong interest in the intersection of these fields. During my studies, I have gained 2 years of work experience in a hypergrowth environment (5x team-level, 3x company-wide during my time) at Celonis, Germany's and New York's highest valued startup. I am looking for a full-time engineering position in the field of machine learning and/or information security.

EXPERIENCE

Junior Information Security Analyst – Celonis (Munich), Part-time

Dec 2020 – Feb 2023

- Performed gap assessments to harmonize audit controls across new and existing cybersecurity frameworks; collected audit evidence to maintain continuous compliance with ISO 27001 and SOC 2.
- Helped develop and test business continuity (contingency) and disaster (emergency) recovery plans
 for business units and externally facing products after conferring with stakeholders to identify critical
 software, hardware, and data assets and risks.
- Assisted with developing information security policies, standard operating procedures, and corporate training material, including the management of automated phishing training for the entire organization.
- Periodically reviewed access rights to cloud systems, assessed the physical security of premises.

Student Assistant – *Introductory Information Security Courses at TUM*

May 2020 – Jan 2021

• Prepared lab topics for students, explained solutions and hosted educational videos. Assisted the rest of the teaching staff during live remote classes for students in Munich and Singapore.

Member and Mentor – adveisor (Technical University of Munich)

Oct 2018 – Jun 2019

Participated in a 1-year soft-skills and personal development programme with outside, professional
coaching, including multiple 3-5 day offsite training sessions. Applied the acquired knowledge by
hosting 10 project management workshops during my second year of university for "mentee" freshers.

EDUCATION

Technical University of Munich (TUM) - Graduated

M.Sc. Electrical Engineering and Information Technology

2020 - 2023

Areas of focus: Machine Learning, Information Security and Automation

Thesis title: Peeking Into the Decision-Making Process in the Human Mind via DL Models

B.Sc. Electrical Engineering and Information Technology

2017 - 2020

Thesis: Compressing ML models to fit on embedded devices (memory & compute constraints)

SKILLS

Languages English, German, Romanian

Coding Python, C/C++, JS/Typescript, Embedded Development

Frameworks TensorFlow, Keras, OpenCV, React, Node.js, Docker, Git, Linux

Security ISO 27001, SOC 2, NIST, OWASP